<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./default.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>MUSCLE Aligner (local)</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Supports running a local muscle executable and integration into the KNIME-PlantCell platform
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>Supports running a local muscle executable and integration into the KNIME-PlantCell platform. This is a very fast multiple sequence
        aligner for both protein and nucleotide sequences. The node provides three performance levels are large series of alignments:
        <ul>
        <li>Maximum accuracy: strongly recommended and the default</li>
        <li>Very fast: without refinement</li>
        <li>Fastest possible: uses the authors recommended settings for the fastest possible alignments. Useful for really large
        alignments with thousands of sequences, but not recommended.</li>
        </ul>
        </intro>
        
        
        <option name="Path to MUSCLE executable">To use this node you must download the MUSCLE program from: <a href="http://www.drive5.com/muscle/downloads.htm">http://www.drive5.com/muscle/downloads.htm</a>
        and then configure this node to the installed program.</option>
        
        <option name="Sequences to align">You have a choice for this column: it can be a collection (list or set) or a sequence column. If the latter,
        all sequences will be aligned together. If its a collection column, each collection cell (ie. row) will be aligned separately.</option>
        
        <option name="Tradeoff">Select the desired performance and accuracy tradeoff. The default is the best quality at the
        expense of performance.</option>
        
        <option name="Report log messages to KNIME console">Report MUSCLE log/debug messages to the KNIME console? Default is off as it can lead to large amount of output and slow performance.</option>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Input data">Must include a set or list of sequences in a single column (see group by node)</inPort>
        <!-- possibly more input ports here-->
        <outPort index="0" name="Aligned sequences">Input data including alignment results. If alignment fails a missing value will be output.</outPort>
        <!-- possibly more output ports here-->
    </ports>    
  
  	<views>
  		<view index="0" name="JalView">Opens the chosen alignment with jalview (see http://www.jalview.org for more details)</view>
  	</views>
  	
</knimeNode>
