<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./default.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>Sequence Extractor</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Similar to the fasta reader, but this node extracts only the specified sequences from the user-supplied input
        table, even from multiple files.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
        Given the input table:
        <table>
        	<tr><th>Filename</th><th>Accession</th></tr>
        	<tr><td>file1.fasta</td><td>seq1</td></tr>
        	<tr><td>file2.fa.gz</td><td>seq2</td></tr>
        </table>
        this node will read <tt>file1.fasta</tt> and look for an entry with ID <tt>seq1</tt>
        and FASTA file <tt>file2.fa.gz</tt> and try to find an ID name <tt>seq2</tt>. 
        Matched entries will have their sequence appended to the input table. This node is really useful
        for locating sequences amongst many different files. Files can be matched on partial name, full name or
        absolute path from the input table.
        </intro>
        
        <option name="FASTA Files">FASTA format file(s) to process. Not all values in the chosen
        column need to be there, but it is recommended you do a <b>Value Counter</b> on the filename
        column to make the list of FASTA files complete. Files may be gzipp'ed or not, but they must have a <tt>.gz</tt>
        extension to be recognised</option>
        
        <option name="Accession Regular Expression">How much data on the <tt>&gt;</tt>-line to interpret as an identifier. This regular
        expression must have exactly one pair of capturing parenthesis <tt>()</tt>. Default RE matches up the first whitespace as the identifier.</option>
       
        <option name="Description Regular Expression">How much data on the <tt>&gt;</tt>-line to interpret as the description. Default RE matches
        everything after the default accession regular expression, but the two can overlap if this is desired.</option>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="FASTA sequences to find">Two columns are used: one with files the other with accessions in the file</inPort>
      
        <outPort index="0" name="Input data and sequence">Same as input table, but with a sequence column appended. Missing values where no match could be found.</outPort>
    </ports>    
    
</knimeNode>
