<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./default.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>NetSurfP@Nectar</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Implements support for the NetSurfP secondary structure prediction via the
        Nectar (http://nectar.org.au) research cloud.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>Implements support for the <a href="http://www.cbs.dtu.dk/services/NetSurfP/">CBS NetSurfP</a> secondary structure prediction via the
        <a href="http://www.nectar.org.au">Nectar research cloud</a>. This server
        has limited resources and is slow to make predictions (often minutes per sequence)
        so can only be used for a small set of proteins. The algorithm is as 
        described in:
        
        <p>
        <br/>
         <i>A  generic  method for assignment of reliability scores applied to solvent accessibility predictions</i>.
       Bent Petersen,  Thomas  Nordahl  Petersen,  Pernille  Andersen,  Morten
       Nielsen and Claus Lundegaard. BMC Structural Biology, 9:51, 2009
        </p>
        
       	<table>
       	<tr>
       		<th>Output:</th><th>Notes:</th>
       	</tr>
       	
       	<tr>
       		<td>Prediction table</td>
       		<td>the raw output from NetSurfP, separated into columns for further analysis</td>
       	</tr>
       	
       	<tr>
       		<td>Annotated sequences</td>
       		<td>the input sequences with additional numeric tracks: each track contains
       		the prediction probability (alpha-helix, beta-strand and coil) associated
       		with every residue in the input sequence. Existing tracks are copied.</td>
       	</tr>
       	</table>
       
        <p>
        <b>Note:</b> 
        <ol>
        	<li>Due to disk space limitations, this node uses NetSurfP with the SwissProt database
        rather than NR70 (70% cluster threshold over the NCBI non-redundant database)</li>
        	<li>Due to firewall restrictions, this node is currently only available to University of Melbourne staff and collaborators</li>
        	<li>This node produces one row for each residue, so it is not recommended for than 100,000 residues</li>
        </ol>
        </p>
        </intro> 
        
        <option name="Biological Sequence">The column of protein sequences to make predictions on. The
        node does not support other sequence types and will reject them</option>
        <option name="Endpoint address">Not currently implemented.</option>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Protein sequence data">Input protein sequence data</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Prediction table">Returns the table of predictions as computed by the algorithm</outPort>
        <outPort index="1" name="Annotated sequences">Each prediction (above cutoff) for every sequence</outPort>
        <!-- possibly more output ports here-->
    </ports>    
  
</knimeNode>
