<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="default.png" type="Visualizer">
    <name>NMF Consensus</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Executes an NMF algorithm to produce a consensus cluster of the user-supplied data matrix.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
        <p>
 		Produces an NMF consensus cluster from the supplied data matrix as described in:
 		<i>Lee, D.D and Seung, H.S. (1999), ‘Learning the parts of objects by nonnegative
            matrix factorization’, Nature 401, 788-793.</i> as implemented by the
        <tt>NMF Consensus</tt> GenePattern module. The module is written in R and is reportedly
        slow, so be careful using this algorithm with more than a thousand genes - it can
        take hours to compute!
        </p>
        
        <p><b>WARNING:</b> by using this node you are making your dataset available to the Internet,
        and trusting that the downloaded heatmap software does no harm to your computer. You
        should only use approved genepattern servers as your organisation.You should only download
        from servers you trust!</p>
        
        <p>
        Once the 5MB of software has downloaded, a heatmap of the supplied numeric matrix
        is presented. This node expects the Row ID's to contain the row (gene) names, 
        the column names are used for the samples. Additionally, a column may be specified
        with descriptions of each gene (row) with user specified text. Only numeric
        columns are selected will display in the matrix.
        </p>
        </intro>
        
        
        <option name="GenePattern Server URL">eg. <a href="http://genepattern.broadinstitute.org/gp">GenePattern public server</a></option>
        <option name="Username">Username (or email address) for authentication. May be blank</option>
        <option name="Password">Password to authenticate to the server.</option>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Matrix to display">Numeric matrix to cluster using NMF</inPort>
    </ports>    
    
    <views>
        <view index="0" name="Output files">Output clustered datasets and graphics</view>
    </views>
</knimeNode>
