<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./default.png" type="Sink">
    <name>add heat to Tree</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Modifies a phylogenetic tree by application of pairwise data to the tree branches, thereby placing colours on regions with the data of interest. 
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>This node creates a new tree from an input tree with branches modified to reflect a colour scheme (configured below)
        and optionally, branch size. Currently there are two colour options: 
        <ul>
        <li>a numeric column translated via a colour gradient to colour the branches. The numeric values supplied can be propagated using
        several functions over the whole tree (average, min, median, maximum) to propagate partial information over the whole tree</li>
        
        <li>using the KNIME row colour to colour the branches connecting the taxa to the rest of the tree. 
        In this case, propagation is not supported.</li>
        </ul>
        </intro>
        
        <option name="Input tree">The tree to apply heat to. The input tree is not modified in any way.</option>

        <option name="Output file">The tree, after decoration with your data, is saved to this location. It is always in 
        <a href="http://www.phyloxml.org">PhyloXML format</a></option>

		<tab name="Heat Settings">
			<option name="Get colours from?">Choose the option to use either a numeric column (which must also be chosen) or get the heat from the
			input table row colours</option>
			
			<option name="Taxa (node) name">Heat values are applied only to nodes with the specified name. The column with the names must be chosen here.
			These node names can be obtained using the Tree Reader node, for example.</option>
			
			<option name="Numeric column">When the node is configured to get colours from a numeric column, this option determines which column
			in the input table is used</option>
			
			<option name="Heat propagation strategy">Currently, the node only supports heat for the branches that connect leaf nodes (taxa/OTUs) to the tree.
			But if you want to apply heat to all branches, you'll need to choose an option here to control how that calculation is done. Choices are limited for now.</option>
			
			<option name="Branch width strategy">Optionally (if not none) you may set the branch width using this option</option>
		</tab>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Input data to label taxa">Input table including (optional) species and domain architecture information.</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Heat statistics">What happened during application of heat: which taxa were used?</outPort>
    </ports>
 
 	<views>
 		<view index="0" name="Archaeopteryx">Display the "hot" tree using Archaeopteryx</view>
 	</views>
</knimeNode>
