<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./default.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>Sequence RPSBLAST+ (Local)</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Supports local execution of RPSBLAST (which must be  installed separately)
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>Supports local execution of <a href="ftp://ftp.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/blast/executables/blast+/LATEST/">rpsblast</a>
        (which must be  installed separately) and direct integration of the RPSBLAST results into
        the KNIME workflow. Query sequences are obtained from the user-specified column.
        Similarly, the database to search is also a .loo file (as made by makeprofiledb from the NCBI BLAST+ suite).
       
        <p>
         
        <b>WARNINGS</b>: 
        <ul>
       		<li>this node is tested with NCBI BLAST+ v2.2.26, other versions are untested</li>
       		<li>the node outputs string columns which must be converted to numeric columns. This
       		ensure no error if a column has a strange value in it. Use the String to Number node for this</li>
       		<li>RPSBLAST can use considerable memory: at least 8GB RAM and a 64-bit Operating System is recommended for the CDD database.</li>
        </ul>
       
        <b>Note:</b> this node does not create a database, you must create it using <i>makeprofiledb</i>, 
        consult the NCBI BLAST+ documentation for information about how to do this.
        </p>
        
        <p>
        This node permits rapid identification of conserved domains which may be used to
        classify protein sequence into a family. Useful for large-scale RNA-seq experiments where
        you want to know what has been identified where you are unable to produce a significant
        hit via sequence similarity search.
        </p>
        
        <p>
        The configure options are not documented here, they are the same as for the
        <b>Sequence BLAST+ (local)</b> node.</p>
		</intro>
        
     </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
    	<inPort index="0" name="Input sequences">Input table with a sequence column to choose</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="BLAST Results">High-Scoring Pair output with all TSV columns preserved</outPort>
   		<outPort index="1" name="Annotated sequences">Sequence cells with annotations representing the domains identified. Only
   		sequences with at least one domain hit are reported here.</outPort>
    </ports>    
   
</knimeNode>
