<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./multialignment-icon-16x16.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>Multiple Sequence Aligner</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>Using an Internet connection, this node aligns the specified 
        sequences (protein, nucleotide) using the chosen algorithm: MUSCLE, T-Coffee
        and Clustal Omega are the only algorithms currently supported.
        
        Never align only two sequences with these algorithms, a much better result will
        usually be produced using a two-sequence only algorithm eg. Smith-Waterman. A separate
        node is available for this.
        
        <p>
        <b>WARNING:</b> this node exposes your data to the Internet and to the European
        Bioinformatics Institute (EBI) and is subject to their terms and conditions. 
        This node is deliberately slow and has limits designed not to operate safely within limits
        imposed by EBI.
        </p>
        
        </intro>
        
        
        <option name="Algorithm">Each algorithm has its own strengths, please consult EBI <a href="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/Tools/msa/">for more details</a></option>
        <option name="Email Address">In case of problems, EBI require an email address
        to contact - a valid email must be provided.</option>
        <option name="List of sequences">Select the collection column of sequences which represent
        what is to be aligned. Typically, this is done using the GroupBy 'list' or 'set' option on the sequences</option>
        <option name="List of accessions">Select the collection column of accessions which represent.
        This <b>must</b> in the same order as the list of sequences</option>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Input data incl. sequences">Input data must contain two collection columns: sequences &amp; accessions</inPort>
        <!-- possibly more input ports here-->
        <outPort index="0" name="Alignment results">Input columns with alignment results</outPort>
        <!-- possibly more output ports here-->
    </ports>    
   
    <views>
            <view index="0" name="Alignment view">View the alignment(s) in the chosen row</view>
    </views>
</knimeNode>
