<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./default.png" type="Manipulator">
     <name>QuickGO Accessor</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Provides an interface to European Bioinformatics Institute QuickGo webservice (Gene Ontology Annotation).
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
        Provides an interface to European Bioinformatics Institute QuickGo web service (Gene Ontology Annotation). The idea being that we
        can perform lookup of the websites, and have the data directly loaded into a KNIME table. This information is always as up-to-date
        as the time this node was last executed,
        since it comes from EBI's computers. More information can be found at <a href="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/QuickGO/">QuickGO@EBI</a>
        
        <p><b>NOTE:</b> the node is deliberately slow (which is not user-configurable) to ensure that EBI's websites
        are not overloaded, and that a KNIME user is not banned from using EBI.</p>
        
        <p><b>NOTE:</b> This node does not provide all the functionality of the website, but it does provide enough, if carefully used,
        to be able to fetch the data. It is <b>strongly</b> recommended that you test with just a few rows and verify results with the website itself
        before processing large datasets.</p>
        
        </intro>
        
        
        <option name="Search Type">Two different searches of QuickGO are available: <i>Term Information</i>, <i>Annotation</i>.
        Term Information can be used to uncover the description of the GO Term ID, Annotation can be used to retrieve existing knowledge about a particular
        protein (as specified by accession) or relating to a particular GO Term.
        </option>
        
        <option name="Column of identifiers">Specify the input data column which contains the identifiers to use for the search. The
        identifiers must be valid for the type of search chosen. Empty or invalid columns will cause the node to abort processing.</option>
  
  		<option name="Identifier column has">either GO terms or protein accessions (eg. from BLAST) to search QuickGO using. 
  		Be <b>sure</b> to set this correctly, for the specified column.</option>
  		
  		<option name="Database">Which database to provide results from. See QuickGO for more details.</option>
  		
  		<option name="All other fields">These fields are passed as-is thru to QuickGO. Set them as described by
  		<a href="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/QuickGO/reference.html">the QuickGO reference manual</a></option>
  		
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Gene input dataset">Input data which contains the column with identifiers to use to perform searches</inPort>
        
        <outPort index="0" name="Gene Ontology dataset">Output data which contains the requested ontological data at output (input data columns are preserved, but
        the node will abort processing if a column already exists of the same name as it adds)</outPort>
        
    </ports>    
    
</knimeNode>
