<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./default.png" type="Manipulator" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.8" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.8 http://knime.org/node/v2.8.xsd">
    <name>ITraQ Analyzer</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Given a (set of) proteomics runs, with identified peptides, proteins and iTRAQ quantitation values this nodes performs an analysis and provides normalised results for the user in easy-to-read format. Based on method published in the scientific literature.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>Implements the method, described at http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/23471484, for analysis of iTRAQ quantitative proteomics
        data. This node requires R to be installed on the computer running KNIME and for the R extension ("HMisc")
        to be installed with the computer. The node will fail to execute unless this is the case.
        
        The node expects a raw (non-normalised) data matrix with each row representing a single peptide identification over
        all the itraq samples. Both 4-plex and 8-plex iTRAQ experiments are supported. This node requires that two channels
        are technical replicates, the other channels can be biological or technical replicates as required. 
        
        The node performs median normalisation of all channels, followed by weighted quantitation at the protein level based
        on normalised peptide results as described by the Hultin Rosenberg paper above. 
        The second output port contain plots produced by the node to help you understand the results of processing. 
        
        This node validates the input data and summarises validation to the KNIME console at the INFO level which
        can be useful when debugging a dataset. The node will abort execution if severe data problems are present in the input data.
        </intro>
        
        
        <option name="Technical replicate #1 iTRAQ channel">description of first option</option>
        <option name="Technical replicate #2 iTRAQ channel">description of second option</option>
        <!-- possibly more options that can also be grouped by tabs -->
        <!--
        <tab name="Standard Options">
            <option name="short name of first option (like in the dialog)">description of first option</option>
            <option name="short name of second option (like in the dialog)">description of second option</option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Advanced Options">
            <option name="short name of first advanced option (like in the dialog)">description of first advanced option</option>
        </tab>
        -->
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Peptide-level iTraq data matrix">Contains a row with: peptide, inferred protein, data matrix attributes (columns)</inPort>
        <!-- possibly more input ports here-->
        <outPort index="0" name="Protein level quantitation">Quantitates each protein over the samples and reports the results</outPort>
        <outPort index="1" name="iTRAQ Analysis QA plots">Contains various plots as produced by the scripts comprising the method. Check the paper for details.</outPort>
        <!-- possibly more output ports here-->
    </ports>    
  
</knimeNode>
