<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./default.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>Representative Protein Selector</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Selects, amongst proteins which share peptides, a representative sequence. In the future, this will provide multiple strategies for doing this: but only one for now. Designed to match the results from the ACPFG String Matcher
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
        This node elects, on the basis of matched peptides from the ACPFG String Matcher node which sequences (ie. rows) are representative
        of the sample. A representative protein is denoted as a <i>tie winner</i> or <i>yes</i> depending on how it won:<br/>
        1. <i>yes</i> means that it had the most peptides amongst sequences featuring a given set of peptides<br/>
        2. <i>tie winner</i> means it was chosen to be the winning sequences among several which feature the same peptides. Currently, the winner in this case is chosen arbitrarily.<br/>
        </intro>
        
        <option name="Peptide Match Column">Name for the column of data which contains the matching peptides for each sequence</option>
        <option name="Selection Strategy">Reserved for future use</option>
        <option name="Accession">Database ID's which are used to group peptide matches by. For this reason, each accession must be in exactly one row or the results will be wrong.</option>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="String Matcher data">Output from the ACPFG String Matcher Node (other data is ok too!)</inPort>
        <!-- possibly more input ports here-->
        <outPort index="0" name="Appended data">Input data with an additional column describing the representative nature of all sequences</outPort>
        <!-- possibly more output ports here-->
    </ports>    
    
</knimeNode>
