<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./default.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>SignalP@Nectar</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Provides a KNIME interface to signal peptide predictions via CBS' signalP algorithms
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
        <p>
        Uses a local server in the Nectar Research cloud to provide much improved throughput compared to the 
        <a href="http://www.cbs.dtu.dk/ws/ws.php?entry=SignalP">CBS server in Denmark</a>. 
        This server provides access to v4.0e of SignalP. This provides two algorithms:
        <ul>
        	<li>Best: an algorithm which tries to distinguish between transmembrane helices
        	and signal peptides</li>
        	<li>no-TM: backward-compatible algorithm with SignalP v3</li>
        </ul>
        </p>
        
        <p>
        <b>Note: </b> this node is only workable for University of Melbourne staff/students and collaborators as it
        uses a server only accessible from on-campus.
        </p>
        
        <p>This algorithm is extensively published and users are <b>strongly recommended</b> to
        read the publications to get the best from the node:</p>
        
        <table>
        	<tr><td>Ver. 4.0</td>
        	<td>"SignalP 4.0 - Discrimination between Signal Peptides and Transmembrane Regions"
       			Thomas  Nordahl  Petersen,  Søren  Brunak, Gunnar von Heijne and Henrik Nielsen. Under review.
       		</td></tr>
       		
       		<tr><td>Ver. 3.0</td>
       		<td>"Improved prediction of signal peptides - SignalP 3.0" Jannick  Dyrloev
       Bendtsen,  Henrik  Nielsen,  Gunnar  von  Heijne  (*) and Soren Brunak.
       Journal of Molecular Biology: accepted 2004.</td></tr>
       
      		<tr><td>Ver. 2.0</td>
       		<td>"Prediction of signal peptides and signal anchors by  a  hidden  Markov
       model",  Henrik  Nielsen  and Anders Krogh In: Proceedings of the Sixth
       International Conference on Intelligent Systems for  Molecular  Biology
       (ISMB 6), AAAI Press, Menlo Park, California, pages 122-130, 1998.</td></tr>
       
       		<tr><td>Ver. 1.1 (original paper)</td>
       		<td> "Identification  of prokaryotic and eukaryotic signal peptides and pre‐
       diction of their cleavage sites", Henrik  Nielsen,  Jacob  Engelbrecht,
       Soren  Brunak  and  Gunnar von Heijne (*) Protein Engineering, vol. 10,
       pages 1-6, 1997.</td>
       		</tr>
        </table>
       
        </intro>
        
        <option name="Protein sequences from">the input must column a protein sequence column (eg. as created by the FASTA Reader), choose the column here</option>
   		<option name="Organism type">Select from eukaryotic (eg. human, plant, animal) or gram+ or gram- (prokaryotic)</option>
   		<option name="SignalP algorithm">Choose from the best (v4) or no-TM (SignalP v3 compatible) algorithm. In some
   		cases you may wish to try both to verify the stability of the prediction</option>
   		<option name="Analyse ... N-terminal residues">How many N-terminal residues to examine for a signal peptide (default 70)</option>
   		<option name="TM Cutoff">Score cutoff for TM network prediction. See the SignalP paper for details
   		on how to set this. Similarly, no-TM cutoff.</option>
   		<option name="Endpoint Address">Reserved for future use</option>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Protein Sequences">Input table with a protein sequence column</inPort>
       	
        <outPort index="0" name="Protein summary">Predictions of phosphorylation sites from NetPhos</outPort>
        <outPort index="1" name="Annotated Sequences">Annotated sequences including prediction sites as a track</outPort>
        <!-- possibly more output ports here-->
    </ports>    
 
</knimeNode>
