<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./default.png" type="Source">
    <name>Taxonomy-aware Fasta Reader</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Used to extract sequences from a FASTA file which match a given column of taxa. Regular expressions can be provided to match the taxa entry from the description in the FASTA file. Taxa desired form the input to the node.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>Naively loads only those sequences from a FASTA file which match one
        of the species names given via the input port. You must configure:
        <ul>
        	<li>FASTA file to load eg. nr.fasta.gz</li>
        	<li>The column which contains only those taxonomy names to accept</li>
        	<li>The regular expression used to extract the taxonomy name from each FASTA sequence.
        	The default regular expression seems to work for NCBI NR fasta-formatted files. This regexp
        	must contain exactly one set of parentheses to match the taxonomy name</li>
        </ul>
        </intro>
        
        
        <option name="FASTA file">FASTA file to process looking for sequences with of a desired species</option>
       
        <option name="Taxonomy regular expression">A regular expression with a single match group (parentheses)
        that describes which part of the description contains the species. By default, all
        data between square brackets (like NCBI NR does) is processed. This option may need
        to be customised if you are using another sequence database eg. UniProtKB</option>
        
        <option name="Accession &amp; Description regexp">Another regular expression which must have two
        match groups (parentheses). The first contains the accession, the second contains the description.
        The default, although not always ideal, usually suffices for most needs.</option>
        
        <option name="Species column">Column containing the <i>desired</i> species to find</option>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Desired species">Taxonomy name column to filter FASTA file for</inPort>
        <!-- possibly more input ports here-->
        <outPort index="0" name="Matching sequences">Matching FASTA sequences, with the taxonomy name that matched</outPort>
        <!-- possibly more output ports here-->
    </ports>    
  
</knimeNode>
