<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./default.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>Wolf PSort@Nectar</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Provides access to a locally installed Wolf PSort (subcellular localisation) prediction server. Please contact the author, Andrew Cassin if you need the wrapper code for the server to use this node. 
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            <p>
		Provides access to a locally available Wolf PSort server for 
		subcellular localisation prediction. This node supports extraction of sub-cellular 
		localisation summary data into the output port, as described by the following publications:
            </p>
                 
            <p>
            Paul Horton, Keun-Joon Park, Takeshi Obayashi, Naoya Fujita, Hajime Harada, C.J. Adams-Collier, &amp; Kenta Nakai,
    		<i>WoLF PSORT: Protein Localization Predictor</i>,
   			Nucleic Acids Research, doi:10.1093/nar/gkm259, 2007.</p>
    
		    <p>
		    Paul Horton, Keun-Joon Park, Takeshi Obayashi &amp; Kenta Nakai,
		    <i>Protein Subcellular Localization Prediction with WoLF PSORT</i>,
		    Proceedings of the 4th Annual Asia Pacific Bioinformatics Conference APBC06, Taipei, Taiwan. pp. 39-48, 2006.
		    </p>
            
            <p>
            <b>Note:</b> this program can make multi-localisation predictions - that is, a protein
            can be predicted to be found in multiple organelles of the cell. Careful comparison with
            single-organelle prediction methods (eg. GolgiP) is required.
            </p>
            
            <p>
        <b>Note: </b> this node is only workable for University of Melbourne staff/students and collaborators as it
        uses a server only accessible from on-campus.
        </p>
        </intro>
        
         <option name="Sequence">Protein sequence to predict on. The sequences are sent to the server in
         batches of 100, each batch is predicted in a single invocation.</option>
        
        <option name="Prediction Model">PSort offers three models tailored to specific species: choose one of
        Animal, Plant or Fungi.</option>
        
        <option name="Endpoint URL">Advanced users: you may specify the host which provides the
        web service to resolve the query. If you do not know what this is, leave as is.</option>
    
 	</fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
	   <inPort  index="0" name="Input data">One column is used to provide the protein sequences to predict on</inPort>

       <outPort index="0" name="Localisation predictions">For each sequence, the localisation(s) as predicted by the remote server</outPort>
    </ports>    
   
</knimeNode>
