<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./default.png" type="Sink">
    <name>Spectra Writer</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Writes a spectra column out to disk for processing with other Mass Spec. software. Supports MGF format but does not guarantee that all input data will be preserved in the created file.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>This node takes data previously loaded by the Spectra Reader and saves it to disk 
        in the specified format. It will "fake" data which required by the file format but is not
        loaded into KNIME: 
        
        <p><b>WARNING:</b> this node does not guarantee to preserve all data present
        in the loaded files as the software is incomplete and imperfect. Use this node at own risk.
        In particular MGF does not preserve SCANS header lines, even if the input data has it. This can
        be useful if you are using software which does not support these headers! It will also reorder the headers
        to support most software packages correctly.</p>
        
        <p>
        This node can create multiple files based on the chosen column: the filename suffix will be chosen
        based on a nominal column. Useful for saving multiple MS/MS fractions at once. The suffix can be
        a column with values like 1, 2, 3, and so on (but it must be a column compatible with strings). It cannot
        contain path separators (eg. \\ under Windows) </p>
        </intro>
        
        <option name="Output filename">The file to save to. If chosen, the suffix will be appended to each file</option>
        <option name="Column to save">Spectra column to save eg. from Spectra Reader or Mascot Reader nodes</option>
        <option name="Overwrite?">The node will abort if an attempt is made to overwrite a file unless this option is checked</option>
        <option name="Output format">Only MGF is supported for now, other formats to come soon</option>
        <option name="Suffix column">Choose none to save a single (combined spectra) file, or to create multiple files with. The column
        must have no more than approx. 40 different values as this will create too many files to be practically useful.</option>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Input spectra">Input spectra to save</inPort>
        <!-- possibly more input ports here-->
    </ports>    
 
</knimeNode>
