<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./default.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>Correlation Calculator</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Unlike the builtin knime node, this can perform large scale correlations by not storing the results into a matrix. I use it for AffyMetrix 21k gene correlations
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>Performs correlation analysis from the first input port, using the list of Row IDs (second input port) defining
        the target variables of interest. Able to perform large-scale correlations as the entire matrix is not stored in memory.
        Two separate algorithms: linear (Pearson correlation) and rank (Spearman's correlation) are available.        
        
        <p>
        If the second input port is empty, then all target variables (ie. numeric columns) in the first input port are assumed
        to be the set of target variables. If the second input is not empty, the RowID's must contain the target variables of
        interest: that is, the column names of variables which you want reported. For example, if the input ports are (in order):
        </p>
      
        <table>
        	<tr><th>Row ID</th><th>Sample1</th><th>Sample2</th><th>Sample3</th></tr>
        	<tr><td>Timepoint 1</td><td>5.0</td><td>10.0</td><td>7.0</td></tr>
        	<tr><td>Timepoint 2</td><td>2.0</td><td>7.0</td><td>9.0</td></tr>
        	<tr><td>Timepoint 3</td><td>0.01</td><td>4.0</td><td>17.0</td></tr>
        	<tr><td>Timepoint 4</td><td>3.0</td><td>2.0</td><td>71.0</td></tr>
        </table>
        
        <table>
        	<tr><th>Row ID</th></tr>
        	<tr><td>Sample1</td></tr>
        	<tr><td>Sample2</td></tr>
        </table>
        
        <p>
        This will cause the node to report any correlation involving <i>Sample1 or Sample2</i> which is
        above the chosen threshold (either positive or negative correlation). Sample3 will only
        be reported if it correlates with either Sample1 or Sample2.
        </p>
        
        <p>
        	<b>Note: </b> this implementation uses Apache Commons Math v3 to perform the correlation. Caveats apply:
        	<a href="http://commons.apache.org/math/apidocs/org/apache/commons/math3/stat/correlation/package-summary.html">see this webpage</a> for more information.
        </p>
        </intro>
        
        
        <option name="Method">Which correlation method to use:
        <ul>
        	<li>Linear (Pearson) product moment correlation coefficient</li>
        	<li>Spearman rank correlation</li>
        </ul>
        </option>
        
        <option name="Minimum magnitude to report">Specify the magnitude of the correlation required
        to be reported eg. 0.5 will report all correlations between [-1,-0.5] and [0.5,1]
        and silently ignore all others. Outliers are only reported for the chosen magnitude as well.</option>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Data to be correlated">Each target variable (column) with datapoints (rows) to be correlated</inPort>
        <inPort index="1" name="Target variable RowIDs">RowIDs to identify variables for correlation</inPort>

		<outPort index="0" name="Output correlations">Contains variables, correlation value, 95%CI and significance test of the correlation</outPort>
		<outPort index="1" name="Grubb outliers">As Pearson correlation can be sensitive to outliers, we report the results of Grubb outlier tests for each correlation pair with at least one outlier</outPort>
    </ports>    
    
</knimeNode>
