<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./default.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>MS/MS Ion Search (beta)</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Performs an MS/MS ion search using MascotEE
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>Performs an MS/MS ion search using MascotEE. This enables search of Mascot generic format (MGF) data
        on the specified mascot server, which has been augmented with an installation of MascotEE. 
        </intro>
        
       	<option name="MascotEE URL">Enter the URL for your MascotEE installation. Press the refresh button
       	if you need the configure screen to update to a recently made change to Mascot, or change the URL</option>
       	
       	<option name="Username &amp; Password">Not currently used, but will be soon to authenticate to MascotEE</option>
       	
       	<option name="Input data">The node provides three options:
       	<ul>
       		<li>Perform a separate mascot search per row of input (whose data file is given in the chosen column)</li>
       		<li>Perform a single mascot search with <b>combined</b> MGF data from the files listed in the chosen column</li>
       		<li>Perform a single mascot search with the chosen peaklists from the input table</li>
       	</ul>
       	In all cases, the input data is passed to mascot in MGF format using the implementation from the Spectra Writer node.
       	</option>
       	
       	<option name="Save peaklists into folder">Specify where MGF data created before search is to be stored. The node
       	will abort if it tries to overwrite an existing file, so it should be an empty folder</option>
       	
       	<option name="Save mascot results into folder">Specify where the Mascot results are to be stored. The node
       	will automatically download and process the results using <a href="https://code.google.com/p/mascotdatfile/">MascotDatFile</a> and load the results into the output ports as well</option>
       	
       	<tab name="Key Settings">
       		<option name="Database to search">Select the sequence database (only those reported from the MascotEE server are shown)</option>
       		<option name="Proteolytic enzyme">Select the enzyme used in the experiment, or None if you dont want mascot to make assumptions
       		about peptides formed from digestion of the protein (slow)</option>
       		<option name="Modifications">Choose the modifications mascot is to consider. Mascot supports both mandatory (fixed)
       		and occasional (variable) modification. Do not choose too many (more than five is realistic) as results will often
       		be hard to interpret</option>
       		<option name="Instrument">Select the available instrument type or leave at default if you are not sure</option>
       		<option name="Mass type">Choose monisotopic if not sure</option>
       	</tab>
       	
       	<tab name="Search Constraints">
       		<option name="Missed cleavages">Enzymatic digestion is not perfect, select the missed cleavage sites permitted here.</option>
       		<option name="Allowed protein mass"></option>
       		<option name="Peptide charge">Only used if the data does not specify the charge state</option>
       		<option name="Peptide tolerance"></option>
       		<option name="MS/MS tolerance"></option>
       		<option name="Taxonomy">if you have a database with many organisms which you dont want to see hits from, this
       		option is your friend: choose the subset of the database which mascot is permitted to report</option>
       	</tab>
       	
       	<tab name="Results Processing">
       		<option name="Report which peptides per query?">Same as the Mascot Reader node</option>
       		<option name="Identity threshold confidence">Same as the Mascot Reader node</option>
       		<option name="Want MS/MS spectra?">Same as the Mascot Reader node</option>
       	</tab>
       	
       	<tab name="Misc.">
       		<option name="Report overview"></option>
       		<option name="Report top ... hits">How many hits to report?</option>
       		<option name="ICAT quantitation"></option>
       		<option name="Precursor"></option>
       	</tab>
       	
       	<tab name="Identification (optional)">
       		<option name="Username">Only letters, numbers and underscore (_) are permitted</option>
       		<option name="Email">Enter an email address, some mascot sites will send an email when the job is finished
       		although PCBRC does not.</option>
       		<option name="Job title">Enter a human description. MascotEE will add a unique ID to this field (which cant be turned off)</option>
       	</tab>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Input table">Input table with search parameters eg. input data</inPort>
        <!-- possibly more input ports here-->
        <outPort index="0" name="Peptide and protein results">Results of ms/ms ion search</outPort>
        <outPort index="1" name="Mascot search parameters">Main configuration parameters used for job, as obtained from results file</outPort>
    </ports>    
   
</knimeNode>
