<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./default.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>Venn Analyzer</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Performs an n-way (3 or 4 recommended) venn analysis based over the values in chosen columns based on a group-by column.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>This node constructs the necessary data for a Venn Diagram based on the input to the node.
        It groups into each "pie" of the venn diagram on the <b>distinct values</b> present in the group-by column,
        up to a maximum number of pies as specified by the configuration of the node. Distinc values are
        processed from the chosen value columns: which may be a list/set cell or string columns.
        <p>
        This node has two output ports: 
        <ol>
        <li>the first with the counts in each pie of the venn diagram</li>
        <li>the second with the values in each category</li>
        </ol>
        This node calculates in terms of set semantics (ie. multiple occurences of a given value count as one).
        </p>
        
        <p>
        More details about venn analyses can be found at <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Venn_diagram">wikipedia</a>.
        Although the node does not currently visualise the venn dataset, enough begs to the author may change that <tt>;-)</tt>.
        </p>
        </intro>
        
        <option name="Group by">The column which contains the names for each pie</option>
        <option name="Use at most N categories">A maximum of N pies will be computed for, if that many distinct values are
        found in the group by column</option>
        <option name="Value columns">you may select multiple columns (either string collection or string cell's may be chosen) for
        construction of the venn data</option>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Input data">Input data (must contain both value columns and group-by column)</inPort>

        <outPort index="0" name="Venn counts">Counts for each portion of the venn diagram</outPort>
       	<outPort index="1" name="Venn values">Values for each category: category names correspond to first output port</outPort>
    </ports>    
   
   <views>
   		<view index="0" name="Venn diagram">Displays an SVG render of the venn diagram, only supports up to four-way diagrams</view>
   </views>
   
</knimeNode>
