<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./default.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>InterPro Accessor</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Accesses the InterPro web service (provided by EBI.ac.uk) with the user-specified settings. This node
        selects the chosen (protein) sequence column and sends each sequence to EBI for analysis. 
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>Accesses the InterPro v5 web service (provided by www.ebi.ac.uk) with the user-specified settings. This node replaces
        the version 4 service and is not backward compatible. But it does offer improved data compared to previous versions. This node
        supports only protein sequences, nucleic acid sequences may be added in future. This node is slow as required by EBI.
        
        <p>
        <b>WARNING</b>: intellectual property may be exposed to the Internet by use of this node.  
        Use this node only if you are satisfied with EBI's <a href="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/Information/termsofuse.html">terms of service</a>.
        </p>
        
        <p>
        Quevillon E., Silventoinen V., Pillai S., Harte N., Mulder N., Apweiler R., Lopez R.<br/>
        <i>InterProScan: protein domains identifier (2005).</i><br/>
        Nucleic Acids Res. 33 (Web Server issue): W116-W120
        </p>
        </intro>
        
        
        <option name="email address">Required by EBI, this ensures they can contact you if there is a problem
        with your jobs during processing</option>
        
        <option name="protein sequence">Select the compatible input column to use for the <b>protein</b> sequences with
        InterProScan</option>
       
        <option name="Algorithms to search via">Perform family identifications using the selected algorithms.
        The default is to use all available algorithms, which is recommended if you are unsure of what you are doing.</option>
     
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Protein sequence input">Input protein sequences for querying via InterPro</inPort>
    	<outPort index="0" name="Site identifications">eg. transmembrane helix predictions or PTM sites</outPort>
        <outPort index="1" name="Classifications">Results of family classification eg. gene ontology or pathway identifications</outPort> 
        <outPort index="2" name="Annotated sequences (incl. InterPro track)">XML output and annotated sequences for each query protein</outPort>
   
    </ports>    
 
</knimeNode>
