<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./default.png" type="Source">
    <name>Biomart Query (experimental)</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Provides access to Biomarts - see http://www.biomart.org for more details
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro> 
        Provides access to Biomarts - see http://www.biomart.org for more details. In essence, this enables
        the user to get wholesale data access very quickly esp. UniProtKB and InterPro to aid with molecular
        annotation.
        
        <p><b>WARNING: </b> dont overload the server - this node is meant to be used carefully. The default is
        to fetch a maximum of 1000 rows to protect the server. Overuse of biomart server may result in
        your organisation banned. This node is currently under active development and will be improved over time
        results may be misleading. Caveat emptor.
        </p>
        
        </intro>
        
        <option name="Available biomarts">Choose the database you wish to obtain data from (InterPRO or UniProtKB are frequently used)</option>
        <option name="Dataset name">Some databases will provide multiple datasets (eg. one per experiment), you may need to choose one here,
        depending on the mart you have chosen.</option>
        
        <option name="Filter">Email address is required by EBI should there be a problem with the jobs. This must be a valid email address or you risk being banned.</option>
    	<option name="Attributes">All EBI WU-BLAST Databases will appear in this list. The entire UniProt (reviewed+not reviewed) is the default</option>
    	<option name="Biomart Server (advanced users only)">Enter a biomart-compatible server (if you run one locally). Not currently supported.</option>
    	<option name="Number of rows to get">To avoid running endless queries, the node is configured to get a maximum of 1000 rows of data.
    	This may be increased as required. Although not recommended you may also specify 0 (zero) to remove this limit.</option>
    
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <outPort index="0" name="Biomart data">Data as provided by biomart</outPort>
    </ports>    
 
</knimeNode>
