<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./default.png" type="Visualizer">
    <name>mzML Surface</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Presents a surface representing RT, m/z and heatmap (eg. identified MS2 spectra) using the sexy jzy3d library. Useful for QA and assessment of mzML-format datasets.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>Presents a surface representing RT, m/z and heatmap (eg. identified MS2 spectra) using the sexy <a href="http://www.jzy3d.org/gallery.php">jzy3d library</a>. 
        Useful for QA and assessment of mzML-format datasets as typically acquired from a LC-MS Mass Spectrometer.
        mzML datasets can be produced for many vendor's Mass Spectrometers - see the ProteoWizard website for
        more details. The surface denotes peaks, passing the chosen threshold, identified by their m/z and RT. Beneath
        the (possibly transparent) surface, on the bottom of the unit cube, is the heatmap constructed from the input to the node.
        
        <p><b>WARNING:</b> this node is experimental. Use at own risk. It uses large amounts of memory for the surface,
        the more you have the better. It may crash, but hopefully it wont crash KNIME. Although hardware-based solutions
        like this can cause system crashes if drivers are buggy. You have been warned.</p>
        
        </intro>
        
       
        
        <option name="mzML files">Select one or more mzML to display as the surface. The surface consists of the
        sum of all MS1 scans in each file organised by peaks in each scan and the scan start time (ie. retention time).</option>
        
        <option name="Peak intensity filter">Select the method (% of TIC, absolute or accept all) and enter
        the value in the box below. The % of TIC method sums all the intensities in a given spectrum and only
        permits those with at least X% of the sum to comprise the surface. The absolute method requires
        an intensity at least the chosen threshold. Accept all admits all peaks.</option>
        
       <option name="Retention time window">Only peaks which fall within this window will comprise the surface (if they
       also meet the other thresholds). In seconds.</option>
       
       <option name="m/z window">Similar to RT window, but this constrains the surface to only the chosen range of M/Z</option>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Input data">Description of first input port...</inPort>
        <!-- possibly more input ports here-->
      
    </ports>    
    <views>
        <view index="0" name="MS Surface">Displays retention time versus MS1 peaks versus sum of intensity across MS1 runs in input files</view>
        <!--view index="1" name="name of second view">Description of second view...</view-->
    </views>
</knimeNode>
