<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./default.png" type="Visualizer">
    <name>Network Creator</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Using JUNG, this node creates a network cell for the input data correlated above a chosen threshold for each target variable.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>Builds a network, one edge for each row, consisting of three sets of user-specified columns to describe:
        <ul>
        	<li>the source node. A node has a name (a unique ID is preferred) and any other columns to describe it. This annotation
        	data will be saved with the network and loaded as needed.</li>
        	<li>the destination node. Like the source node this may be annotated with arbitrary columns. But a given column should
        	not be used for both ie. specific to a particular node!</li>
        	<li>the connection (edge) between them. This may also be annotated and optionally a distance associated with the connection</li>
        </ul>
        
        <p>For instance, using this node after a <b>Correlation Calculator</b> can
        give a network of correlations which may provide biological insight. The network can be saved
        in <a href="http://graphml.graphdrawing.org/">GraphML format</a> or opened in 
        <a href="https://gephi.org/">a visualisation program like Gephi</a> or 
        <a href="http://www.cytoscape.org">Cytoscape</a>. For now, only graphs with a single edge between
        source and destination are supported: an error will be thrown if this constraint is violated. This means
        you must eliminate redundancy before using this node eg. via <b>GroupBy (First)</b>. 
        </p>
        </intro>
        
        
        <option name="Options">In this tab you may configure how table row colours are assigned to the view: used to colour nodes or edges.
        Show edge distance can be used to display the correlation values on the path between the two nodes (can create a cluttered graph).
        Paint edges as gradient "fades" the edges near nodes which can be somewhat neater. Missing values will be ignored.</option>
        
        <option name="Source nodes">Here you need to select the column which provides the names for the source nodes. If you
        want a timecourse bar chart to be displayed, select the list of values column here. Other annotations for the source nodes ONLY
        can be added also. Missing values will be ignored.</option>
        
   		<option name="Destination nodes">Similar options as per source nodes</option>
   		
   		<option name="Edges">Specify the distance (if any is computed) for the edge. This does <b>not</b> influence the layout as it is
   		for visualisation only. Columns describing the edge can also be added here. Missing values will be ignored.</option>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Input columns">One column should contain the source node (eg. gene or protein name), and another column the destination. </inPort>
        <!-- possibly more input ports here-->
        <outPort index="0" name="Network output">A (small) table with only a network name and network graph output</outPort>
        <!-- possibly more output ports here-->
    </ports>    
    <views>
        <view index="0" name="Interactive view">Display the graph with edge lengths preportional to the chosen distance column.</view>
    </views>
</knimeNode>
