<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./default.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>TMHMM@Nectar</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Provides a KNIME interface to transmembrane helice(s) predictions server installed locally
        (and not via web services to CBS)
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>This node provides access to Protein Sequence TM helix prediction as described in:
        <p>
        <i>Predicting transmembrane protein topology with a hidden Markov model: Application 
			to complete genomes</i>. A. Krogh, B. Larsson, G. von Heijne, and E. L. L. Sonnhammer. 
			J. Mol. Biol., 305(3):567-580, January 2001.<br/>
			PDF: http://www.binf.ku.dk/krogh/publications/pdf/KroghEtal01.pdf
		<br/>
			<i>A hidden Markov model for predicting transmembrane helices in protein sequences. </i>
			E. L.L. Sonnhammer, G. von Heijne, and A. Krogh.
			In J. Glasgow, T. Littlejohn, F. Major, R. Lathrop, D. Sankoff, and C. Sensen, editors, 
			Proceedings of the Sixth International Conference on Intelligent Systems for Molecular Biology, 
			pages 175-182, Menlo Park, CA, 1998. AAAI Press. <br/>
			PDF: http://www.binf.ku.dk/krogh/publications/ps/SonnhammerEtal98.pdf
			
        </p>
        
        <p>
        This node provides textual and bitvector output of the predicted helices for subsequent computation.
        </p>
        
        <p>
        <b>Note: </b> this node is only workable for University of Melbourne staff/students and collaborators as it
        uses a server only accessible from on-campus.
        </p>
        </intro>
        
        
        <option name="Protein sequences">Column to obtain the protein sequences from. The RowID's will be
        used to identify each sequence, but they <b>must</b> have no whitespace in them.</option>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Protein Sequences">Input table must contain one String column with protein (amino acid) sequences.
        Unknown residues (eg. <tt>X</tt>) in sequences are not recommended.</inPort>
       
        <outPort index="0" name="Protein summary">Summary output from TMHMM for each sequence</outPort>
        <outPort index="1" name="Annotated Sequences">Annotated sequence with predicted locations for helices, inside and outside orientations as computed by TMHMM</outPort>
        <!-- possibly more output ports here-->
    </ports>    
 
</knimeNode>
