<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./default.png" type="Sink">
    <name>Tree2PhyloXML Writer</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Saves a tree format (eg. Newick or PhyloXML) tree with decorated data from the input table
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>Saves an input tree file (eg. Newick or PhyloXML format) tree with decorated data from the input table
        as a <a href="http://www.phyloxml.org">PhyloXML</a> document. The document can be opened at the conclusion of processing
        if this is desired.</intro>
        
        
        <option name="Tree to decorate">Enter the newick file which you wish to use as the source (gene) tree. It will not be modified.</option>
        <option name="Output file">The tree, after decoration with your data, is saved to this location. Always <a href="http://www.phyloxml.org">PhyloXML format</a></option>
        <option name="Overwrite existing output file?">If checked, the node will overwrite an existing output file</option>
        <option name="Start Archaeopteryx">If checked, display the adjusted tree in archaeopteryx once the execution is complete. Currently
        disabled as it can crash KNIME on some platforms.</option>
        <option name="Tree labels">Select the sequence column which provided taxa for the tree. The phyloxml can include this
        sequence if the 'include sequence' button is checked</option>
        <option name="Match taxa names (advanced users only)">This option can be used to match part of the input tree label to the input data. By default,
        all the taxa names from the newick files are matched against input data.</option>
       
        <tab name="Decorations of output tree">
        <option name="Scientific species names">Choose the column (or none) which provides scientific species names</option>
        <option name="Image URLs">Each taxa can have an image, here you can choose which column provides the URL for each taxa (or none)</option>
        <option name="Branch widths determined by unique ...">Select the column (or none if you dont want branch widths set)
        to accumulate branch widths. A unique count of values for the taxa underneath each node in the tree is used to set
        the branch width. A square root transform is applied to ensure no branch is too wide.
        This requires a large amount of memory (and time for really large trees).</option>
        </tab>
        
        <tab name="Domain Labelling">
        <option name="Label for domains">Domain architecture eg. structural features for each sequence can be labelled with three parallel
        lists. This vector provides a list of strings (which should be short for clarity) of the features on the sequence to show. All
        three lists (labels, start &amp; end positions) must have the same number of values. Missing values in lists must not be present. GroupBy "list" aggregation function can be used to create the required cell</option>
        <option name="Start positions">A list of values which describe the start positions for each feature. GroupBy "list" aggregation function can be used
        to create the required cell</option>
    
        <option name="End positions">A list of values which describe the end position of each feature. GroupBy "list" aggregation function can be used to create the required cell</option>
        </tab>
        
        <tab name="Vector Data">
        	<option name="Collection of numeric values">This column (which must be a collection of numeric cells) is mapped
        	onto the clade owning the given taxa in the tree. The result in the phyloxml is a series of heatmaps one per taxa
        	of the collection. Collections may be omitted (ie. missing values) but all items in the collection should be valid
        	numeric values. Set collections are not recommended as the order will be indeterminate in the heatmap. An example
        	of this type of display can be <a href="https://sites.google.com/site/cmzmasek/home/software/archaeopteryx/documentation#TOC-Reading-and-Displaying-of-Expression-and-Other-Vector-Data">found here</a>
        	</option>
        </tab>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Input data to label taxa">Input table including (optional) species and domain architecture information.</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Decoration statistics">What happened during decoration: how many taxa were annotated?</outPort>
    </ports>
 
 	<view>
 		<view index="0" name="Archaeopteryx">Load the tree view into Archaeopteryx. See www.phyloxml.org for details.</view>
 	</view>
</knimeNode>
